Hey!
喂
You there! The Paladin with the roughed-up equipment!
那位裝備破爛的聖騎士玩家
Would you like me to fix your things?
要不要我幫你修呢？
If you're a newbie, I'll give you a deal.
新手可以算便宜一點哦
I'm Princess Ruri!
我叫瑠璃姬
Nice to meet you, Ms. Paladin!
幸會，聖騎士玩家
There's something I want to tell you.
我有話想跟你說
Do you have time?
方便嗎？
ORIGINAL STORY BY MASHIRO
（原作：Mashiro）
Where are we?!
這是哪裡？
Don't spook me like that!
嚇死我了
I thought you were about to ask me out.
以為是要給我愛的告白
Oh, sorry! Did I give off that vibe?
抱歉，剛才的氣氛是這樣嗎？
That's the only vibe you gave off.
怎麼想都是那種氣氛
I said I'm sorry…
真是對不起
And…?
所以呢？
What did you want to tell me?
你要跟我說什麼？
Well, you see…
就是…
TEN MINUTES LATER
（十分鐘後）
Akane means to say she's in love!
茜說她有喜歡的人了
Oh, that's a surprise!
是哦，嚇我一跳
Congratulations!
恭喜啊
Shall I guess who it is?
讓我來猜猜對象吧
Don't say it.
不要說出來
I'm quite moved, you know.
總覺得好感慨啊
When I first met you,
我剛認識Akane的時候
you were wandering around the game world looking jaded.
你一個人沒趣地在遊戲裡晃來晃去
Thinking back,
現在仔細想想
you were probably still in turmoil from your breakup.
那時你應該剛被甩，心煩意亂吧
But you've recovered, huh?
你重新振作起來了呢
Well done.
真了不起
Even so, she's still fretting over
但她還在尋找自己被甩的理由
the reason her boyfriend dumped her!
在那邊煩惱老半天
Huh? What's that about?
怎麼回事？
That's looking backwards!
感覺好消極
Um…
那個…
It might sound that way,
你聽起來可能是那樣
but I just want to know if I have any bad qualities to fix.
但我只是想知道自己有什麼缺點
From my perspective,
我姑且…
I'm looking to the future.
覺得自己還算積極啦
That's why I…
所以…也就是說…
It's just…
應該說我只是…
When I saw your face, Eita…
一看到瑛太的臉
I wanted to talk to Princess Ruri!
就也想告訴瑠璃姬這件事
The ones who picked me up when I was down
因為在我難過的時候
were Momo and Princess Ruri.
是小桃和瑠璃姬安慰了我
When I realized I was in love,
所以我想告訴你們
I wanted to tell you both.
我有了喜歡的人
Sure.
嗯
The one you like
Akane喜歡的那個人
is someone I've known for a long time.
我認識他很久了
He's a good guy.
他是個好人哦
Everyone concentrates on his looks,
雖然大家總是提及他的外表
but his kindness is pretty rare too.
但很少有人像他那麼溫柔
I guess you know that.
你早就知道了吧，不過…
But it's true.
他真的就是那樣
He's a block head, but he's got a big heart.
雖然遲鈍，心胸也很寬大
Just be your true self.
你保持原本的作風就行了
In fact, too direct is probably just right.
直率過頭的態度對他正好
Give it your best shot!
要加油哦
If he rejects you, Momo and I are here.
如果被甩，還有我跟小桃在
He's right, Akane!
對啊，茜
A woman must be bold!
女人就要有膽量
Act first, ask questions later!
一有念頭，就要立即行動
In fact, you should go and tell him right now!
乾脆現在就去告白吧
Yeah! She's right!
沒錯！
I… understand.
我…我明白了
I'll go all or nothing!
我就去奮力一搏吧
Hope it's all and not nothing.
祈禱你盡量別粉身碎骨
I'll do my best to make it all!
我會努力別粉身碎骨的
Thanks! I adore you both!
謝謝，最愛你們了
I hope it's all, not nothing.
希望她別粉身碎骨了
Well, who can really say.
天曉得，這實在難說
Let me reintroduce myself. I'm Momoko Maeda.
你好，重新自我介紹，我叫前田桃子
And I'm Eita Sasaki.
我是佐佐木瑛太
I'm a 20-year old college student
我是二十歲大學生
and I want to get married.
正在認真找結婚對象
OH YEAH?
（是哦）
Do you have a girlfriend?
你有女友嗎？
When did I… start falling for him?
我是何時喜歡上他的？
Even looking back, I can't remember.
不管怎麼想，也想不太起來
It's just that…
但是…
seeing him finally smile
因為他很少會笑
makes me happy.
每次看到他笑，我就會很高興
IT'S CROWDED…
（人好多…）
Pretending not to notice,
我假裝沒發現自己的心意
or telling myself he's just a friend…
對自己說我們只是朋友
Hiding my feelings like that
就算這樣騙自己
was probably pointless.
也沒什麼意義呢
Oh, I'm sorry!
抱歉
Calm down!
我太焦急了
Are you okay?
你沒事吧？
I'm fine now.
我已經沒事了
Yeah?
來了
Huh?
奇怪？
Y-Yo!
喲
Hi.
你好
Um…
請問…
Do you need something?
你有什麼事嗎？
-Actually, there's something… -Oh, hello there!
-我跟你說，其實今天… -哎呀
-That I really want to tell you. -Time for your walk, already?
-我有話一定要告訴你… -加藤爺爺，到你散步的時間啦？
-Um… -What'd you say?
-就是… -什麼？
Is it time for your walk, already?
到你散步的時間啦？
-Um… -Oh, hello!
-那個… -你好
-Say, today-- -Today?
今天…
Today, I wanted to…
就是…今天…
-It's a warm day, isn't it? -Indeed!
-今天天氣… -今天很暖和吧？
-I wish every day could be this warm! -Um…
-要是每天都像今天一樣暖就好了 -那個…
It really is warm…
今天真的很暖和…
-Akane… -Yes?!
-茜 -什麼事？
-Forgive me, I have to go to cram school. -At the station.
-抱歉，我現在該去補習班了 -我前陣子在車站前
-You do? -I saw your granddaughter, Emi!
-是這樣嗎？ -有看到您的孫女繪美
Since it's a Saturday, I thought you would be free.
抱歉，因為今天週六 我以為你一定放假
-I'm happy to listen though. -Did you hear me? Emi!
-我現在可以聽你說 -有聽懂嗎？就是繪美
Can we talk on the way to the station?
但我必須一邊往車站走，可以嗎？
-She's your granddaughter, right? -Oh, yes!
（好冷 請進吧）
Actually, couldn't we have talked over the phone?
話說不能用電話講嗎？
You fool.
我真蠢
He has his own routine.
山田也有自己的事
What was I thinking?
我卻這麼魯莽
Sorry, I'll come back another--
抱歉，我之後再來…
I hear Emi is in the band now!
聽說繪美在玩樂團
Yes, but it will rain later.
不過晚上會下雨啊
I just need to change.
我馬上去換衣服
Please wait here.
你等我一下
R-Right…
好
Sorry to bother you when you're busy!
抱歉哦，挑你這麼忙的時候來
He startled me…
嚇我一跳
It seems like your cold is better.
話說你的感冒好了耶
Yeah! Thanks to you.
是啊，託你的福
Oh yeah. I wanted to make it up--
對了，關於謝禮…
Turn the other way!
我轉過去好了
-Sorry, I'm ready. -Right!
-讓你久等了 -是的
So, what's up?
所以你要說什麼？
Oh, sorry. I've been thinking of where to start.
抱歉，我還在想該怎麼開口
I DIDN'T PLAN TO DO THIS OUT HERE
（我沒想到場景會是在街上）
No time to spare.
沒時間了
I have to tell him now.
必須快點說出來
It's what I came here to do.
我就是為此而來的
But then…
可是…
There's no need to force it out in the middle of town
其實也不必挑這麼匆忙的時候
when we're short on time.
硬是在街上向他開口
Do it another day…
等下次…
When we have more time…
有時間再說…
Akane!
茜！
The light… is red.
現在是紅燈
S-Sorry…
對…對不起
Are you okay?
你沒事吧？
You seem really spaced out.
你今天常恍神
It's no good. My attention span…
不行，精神好渙散
Sorry.
抱歉
Being together is only going to cause him trouble
就算像這樣爭取共處時間
if all I can do is buy time.
也只會給山田添麻煩
Do it another day.
下次再說吧
Um… maybe today isn't the best…
那個…我想今天還是…
Green light.
綠燈了
Just like this…
乾脆保持現狀
Without saying a thing…
別說多餘的話
I could let him spoil me with his kindness.
繼續依賴他的體貼好了
But hiding my feelings
像這樣隱藏自己的心意
just doesn't seem fair.
實在有點卑鄙
Well, this is the station.
那我要去搭電車了
You didn't get a chance to talk.
結果還是無法聽你說
I'm sorry.
真是抱歉
I was too worried about being late.
因為快遲到了，就急著趕路
No, I was acting weird.
不，是我太奇怪了
You really were.
的確是那樣
IGNORING THE TRAFFIC LIGHT WAS CRAZY
（不看紅綠燈真的有點糟）
Well then, next time…
那麼…下次再聊
Is it important?
那是很重要的事嗎？
Maybe, after class…
等補習班下課…
Though it will be late…
雖然這樣有點晚了
If you don't mind, I'll call you.
要是不介意，我可以打給你
If you really want to talk today…
假如你想在今天談的話
Are you sure? Won't you be tired?
可以嗎？你不會累嗎？
Not too tired to listen.
如果只是聽你說話，倒無所謂
Though I'm not the best conversation partner.
但我很懷疑自己
SHORT RESPONSE MACHINE
（只會附和對方）
That'd be great!
太好了
I'll be going, then.
那我要走了
Have a good day!
路上小心
Study hard!
上課要加油哦
BYE-BYE!
（拜拜）
Bad weather, suddenly…
天氣好像突然就變糟了
It was sunny just a moment ago.
明明剛才還是晴天
That'll be all for today.
今天就上到這裡
Please do the follow-up exercises in your textbooks.
回去要做好參考書的應用題哦
Rain, huh?
下雨了啊
What are we going to do, Yamada? It's pouring.
山田，要怎麼辦？雨下得這麼大
I have a folding umbrella.
我自己有帶折傘
My hero!
太神了吧
Walk with me, will you?
我們一起共撐吧
Fine.
可以啊
You okay, Ms. President?
班長，那你呢？
I don't have an umbrella.
我也沒帶傘
I'm planning to run home.
想說用跑的回去
Isn't that a little extreme?
也太堅強了吧
I have no choice.
沒辦法
The rights to Yamada's umbrella…
和山田一起撐傘的權利
go to you.
就讓給班長吧
Fine, right Yamada?
山田，可以吧？
Either one of you is okay with me.
我都沒差啊
That wouldn't be fair. The two of you should go.
怎麼好意思？你們一起回去吧
I can't leave a lady in distress.
不，我不能這樣拋下淑女
Plus, it's a chance to go home with him.
這是你們一起回去的機會耶
Don't let it slip away!
要懂得把握啊
Thanks but no thanks.
你不用故意幫我製造機會
You'll only make him suspicious.
會害山田同學覺得奇怪的
If you don't make him a little suspicious,
不讓他稍微覺得奇怪
things will go nowhere.
什麼都不會發生吧？
Especially in your case.
尤其是對你來說
I guess they can't reach a decision.
他們在互讓對方，談不出結果嗎？
Maybe I'll give them the umbrella
乾脆把傘給他們
and run home myself.
我自己用跑的好了
I WANNA GO HOME…
（好想回家…）
Yamada-kun!
山田同學
Um…
那個…
On second thought,
還是想麻煩你
can I walk with you to the station?
能不能和我一起共撐到車站？
So anyway, I tried that new game.
然後我玩了那個新遊戲
It was a beta, so there were still a lot of bugs,
因為還是測試版，有很多BUG
but it seems pretty fun.
但感覺非常有趣
Hurry up!
快一點啦
Give me a second!
等等我
You're too slow, Saki!
佐紀，你好慢
I can't run in these shoes!
鞋子會滑啦
Seriously?
真是的
Is she someone you know?
是你認識的人嗎？
Huh?
咦？
You were staring at that girl who was running.
剛才你一直盯著跑過去的那個人
I wasn't.
你誤會了
Tsubaki,
椿同學
please use the umbrella on your own.
這把傘還是給你一個人撐好了
Huh, why?
為什麼？
There's no sense in you getting wet. Go ahead.
你被淋濕就沒意義了，拿去用吧
But what about you?
怎麼可以，那你呢？
I'm going to run.
我用跑的回去
-But-- -I'm almost at my station.
-可是…那個… -就快到車站了
Wait!
等等
Yamada-kun, wait!
山田同學，等一下
Excuse me…
不好意思…
My glasses…
眼鏡…
I can't see.
我看不見
There's a crack.
摔裂了
Are you okay?
你沒事吧？
I like you.
喜歡你
Huh?
什麼？
I'm sorry for being a bother.
抱歉，讓你困擾了
But… please…
但是求求你
Just for today…
希望在今天
Let me be in your thoughts.
你能思考一下我的事
I WON'T BE ABLE TO TALK TODAY.
（今天沒辦法和你講電話了）
LET'S DO IT WHEN WE HAVE TIME. SORRY.
（下次有時間再聽你說，抱歉）
That was some rain yesterday.
昨天啊，雨下得很大吧？
I was asleep, but the noise woke me up.
瑠奈原本在睡覺，就被吵醒了
And then I couldn't get back to sleep--
而且之後完全睡不著
Runa, you've lost focus, haven't you?
瑠奈，你沒在專心唸書了吧？
Yup! I sure have!
嗯，完全沒有
I'm sure you're tired,
讀書辛苦了
so I bought some donuts.
我買了甜甜圈
-Both of you, help yourselves! -Yay!
-你們也吃吧 -好耶！
Yamada, I know you have your own exams. Thanks for this.
山田明明也是考生，真是感謝你
Runa won't accept any teacher other than you.
因為瑠奈吵著說要請你當家教
She must really like you!
看來她真的很喜歡你
Seeing you two like this,
話說這樣看起來
I can't help but think you look good together.
你們真的好登對哦
Right, big brother?
對吧，哥哥？
Now now, Mom.
媽媽真討厭
Your ambitions are naked!
你的野心表露無遺
-What do you mean? -Beats me.
-你指什麼？ -不知道
All I said was that they look good together.
我只是說他們很登對而已
-Right. That's all. -Any idea what they're talking about?
-是啊… -你知道他們在說什麼嗎？
Who knows…?
天曉得
It must be some sort of joke.
應該是在開什麼玩笑吧
By the way, Akito… yesterday…
對了，秋斗，話說昨天…
A girl confessed to you, didn't they?
你被女生告白了吧
HUH? I CAN'T SOLVE THIS ONE.
（奇怪？）
How did you know?
你怎麼知道？
I know everything.
我什麼都知道哦
So Akane really told him.
Akane還真的告白了啊
She sure is something.
她真是不得了
And…? What was your answer?
然後呢？你怎麼回答？
-It's none of your business. -Of course it is.
-等等，這和你無關吧 -有關吧
Wait, is it?
有關嗎？
I'm thinking about it.
我正在思考
I thought you might be interested.
我本來以為你也有意思
-You get along well. -I guess…
-畢竟你們也很要好 -也是啦
You're always so indecisive.
真是優柔寡斷的傢伙
THINKING TOO LONG WON'T DO YOU ANY GOOD
（竟然還要花時間思考）
You better give her a straight answer soon.
如果不早點回答清楚
The worst thing you can do is play with another person's feelings.
像這樣給對方希望，玩弄人家 是最要不得的哦
I'm not playing!
我才沒那樣做
-Uh oh, Eita. You've made him mad again. -What?!
笨蛋瑛太又惹山田生氣了，嘻嘻
I'm sorry, Akito! Don't be angry!
抱歉，秋秋！不要生氣啦！
-Here, have these donuts! -Those are mine!
-甜甜圈給你吃！ -那是瑠奈的甜甜圈！
The number you are calling
您所撥的電話號碼
is unavailable…
目前收不到訊號或是未開機…
Huh?
奇怪？
Akane! Akane!
小茜…
Look… outside!
我跟你說，在外面哦…
Hey, Yamada!
喂，山田
What brings you here?
你在做什麼？
It's not so often
真難得耶
that you come to our store.
竟然會來我打工的超商
Shouldn't you be working?
你的工作沒問題嗎？
I switched to outside duty.
我被換來整理外面
Were you perhaps looking for me?
看來你是來見我的吧？
Just kidding!
開玩笑的啦
Yeah.
是的
I called you just now,
我剛才打電話給你
but it didn't connect.
可是沒有接通
Oh… sorry about that.
這樣啊，真是抱歉
My phone was at 3% when I left home.
我出門時，手機只剩3%電了
That's fine.
沒關係
If I happened to see you,
我想說如果能見到面
I wanted to apologize for yesterday.
就要為昨天的事跟你道歉
That's…
這樣啊…
I'm not upset.
我沒放在心上啊
It wasn't that important.
又沒什麼大不了的
Actually, I talked to Momo about it yesterday.
而且昨天小桃有聽我說了
I feel much better now.
已經讓我暢快多了
But more important than that…
比起這件事
You seem kind of down today.
你今天好像沒什麼精神
What's the matter?
怎麼了嗎？
Do I?
有嗎？
I feel perfectly normal.
和平常一樣啊
You're completely different!
完全不一樣
Your voice is a monotone…
聲音毫無生氣
Well, it always is...
雖然你本來就這樣
But you're not saying much…
也不怎麼說話
Well, you never do, but…
但你原來也是這樣
The usual Yamada is like this.
平常的山田是這樣
But today, you're like this.
今天的山田是這樣
I DON'T SEE THE DIFFERENCE
（完全看不出差別）
EVEN SO, SHE'S SHARP
（但你還真強）
These days…
最近…
I've been busy. Maybe I'm tired.
因為有點忙，大概是累了吧
Or something like that.
我也不曉得
Tired from exam studying?
準備大考累壞了吧
It must be tough.
真是辛苦啊
He's in a different league from me.
和我是不同世界的煩惱
I see…
這樣啊
That reminds me! The other day,
對了，我最近啊
I upgraded my equipment in FOS.
把FOS內的裝備換新了哦
I wanted to show off to you,
我一直想秀給山田看
but you never log in these days.
但你都沒上線
I got myself a good sword.
我選了一把好劍哦
What kind is it?
是什麼樣的裝備？
What kind…
什麼樣的裝備？
you ask?
什麼意思？
Like the weapon's rank or type.
就是武器的等級或種類
OR WHETHER IT'S EVEN REAL…
（還有稀有度等等）
Well…
這個嘛
Give me your hand.
把手伸出來
-Is that a permanent marker? -Give me your hand.
-那是油性筆嗎？ -把手伸出來
Bosses leave behind good plunder, don't they?
BOSS會掉很多好東西呢
I finally understand now
我最近總算開始明白
why you always hunt them.
為何山田老在打BOSS
Well, the chances are still pretty low.
只是掉寶機率有點低
Right, and that's why, when they drop something nice,
沒錯…所以只要掉了好東西
it makes you jump for joy.
就會高興得不得了，甚至會發抖吧？
I don't know what's wrong,
雖然我不太懂
but cheer up!
希望你打起精神來
Return to your usual unflappable self.
恢復成那個難以捉摸的山田吧
I'LL DRAW MY CHARACTER TOO
（也畫一下我的角色吧）
WHAT DO MY CLOTHES LOOK LIKE AGAIN?
（服裝是穿什麼來著？）
That's how I seem to you?
我看起來是那樣啊
I only keep quiet,
我不太開口說話
because I'm scared of saying the wrong thing.
只是怕自己說出多餘的話
I can't read people's feelings deeply,
我無法解讀他人的心情
and I don't understand jokes a lot of the time.
也常常聽不懂玩笑話
I think that
只是個無聊的傢伙
just makes me dull.
我自己是這麼認為
Well, in my case…
對我來說
The way you sometimes make shrewd comments
你偶爾會精準地吐槽
is uh…
該怎麼說…
something I like.
我蠻喜歡的
Or when we're all together, even if you're quiet,
和大家待在一起時，你就算不說話
you watch out for everyone.
我知道你會觀察四周，顧慮每個人
I know you try to help when people are in need.
看到別人有難，你也會幫助對方
Because you helped me a lot.
我就被你救過好幾次
There's nothing dull about that.
你一點也不無聊哦
I told you before, didn't I?
我說過你很有趣吧？
You can believe me.
相信我吧
I mean it!
我說真的
Okay?
好嗎？
I sigh
早上一醒來
when I wake up in the morning.
就會先嘆口氣
At some point, it became a habit.
這不知不覺成了我的習慣
Isn't love…
我猜戀愛…
Yukari,
由香里
are you going out at this time of night?
這麼晚了，你要出門嗎？
Just for a bit.
我有點事
I made a promise to a friend.
跟朋友約好了
Come home right away, okay?
結束後要馬上回來哦
Isn't it supposed to be more fun than this?
一定是更開心的事才對